<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Causes &amp; Effects</title>
    <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Causes &amp; Effects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:21:57 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I Use Pyenv and Pipenv for All Python Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/pyenv-pipenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/pyenv-pipenv/</guid>
      <description>My Python workflow is constantly changing as new tools emerge to make things faster and easier. In this post, I want to share my current workflow as of November 2020.
My current step zero workflow for any project or even a fresh OS relies on Pyenv and Pipenv, and here is how:
Installing Pyenv brew install pyenv Once pyenv is installed, you can run the bare command and list all of the options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Worrying and Git Yolo</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/yolo-git-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 10:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/yolo-git-2020/</guid>
      <description>Git yolo has changed my life for the better. It saves me tons of time. You never have to type in a commit comment again.
Here is how to get the yolo alias working:
You need to edit your gitconfig dotfile that is located at ~/.gitconfig.
Mine before:
$ cat ~/.gitconfig # This is Git&#39;s per-user configuration file. [user] # Please adapt and uncomment the following lines: name = jamesacampbell email = james@jamescampbell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Music from the Terminal</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/streaming-music-from-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 21:19:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/streaming-music-from-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember Rdio? It was a better than Spotify at streaming music back in 2012.
In 2013, Entertainment Weekly compared a number of music services and judged Rdio the best, grading it &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; and writing that it had &amp;ldquo;by far the best app and online interface, making database searching and playlist curation easy&amp;rdquo; - source
Rdio ended up not finding the right business model, or spending too much of its 200 million, or who knows what, but it filed for bankruptcy in 2015 and Pandora purchased it and all of its assets for 75 million cash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forever Things</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/forever-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 23:19:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/forever-things/</guid>
      <description>I love brass. Brass is a hard metal that will outlast me. It is strange to think about things that will exist after we are gone. I own a Kaweco pen that is brass. Assuming I buy ink refills, I never have to buy a pen again.
That is a single example that explains the idea behind this article. What thing can you acquire once, and then never have to buy a newer version again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Photography and Joy</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/on-photography-and-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 10:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/on-photography-and-joy/</guid>
      <description>To Begin, What Do I Call Myself Online?
The problem with doing many things is that I have trouble filling in my bio information on social networking sites. Do I say &amp;lsquo;photographer&amp;rsquo; even though it is not my day job? Do I say &amp;lsquo;web developer&amp;rsquo; even though a lot of the times I am just solving issues for clients and not actually coding? Do I say founder of InstantDC.com and curator of photo exhibitions, even though this is usually once or twice a year?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013, The Year We Missed</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/2013-year-we-missed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 04:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/2013-year-we-missed/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, we looked pretty ridiculous standing around staring at our phones, tablets, phablets, and iPads.
My goal in this post is to share photos I have curated that document the phenomenon of humans interacting with new technology.
Since I believe I am a better curator than writer, I will try to keep the words to a minimum.
New technology is great, but we need to figure out what it means and how it fits into our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Flickr is My Online Backup Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/why-flickr-backup-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 10:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/why-flickr-backup-solution/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about Flickr&amp;rsquo;s new redesign enough. There are some positives about the service that still out-do any other online photo sharing website.
For example, I am one of the lucky ones who have been grandfathered into Flickr&amp;rsquo;s unlimited photo plan when my Pro plan was renewed earlier this year. This means that for $25 per year I get unlimited photo storage.
This fact, coupled with the auto-upload feature in the Flickr app for the iPhone means I have everything I need to backup and store all of my photos taken on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Daily News Routine in 2013</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/daily-news-routine-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 10:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/daily-news-routine-2013/</guid>
      <description>It is impossible for anyone to keep up with everything that happens every single day.
Back in 2008, stuck between Youtube videos, tweets, Flickr contacts, etcetera, I realized this. I decided to filter out what I really needed daily through a tight collection of RSS feeds and email subscriptions. I started with an initial list of 10 to 20 in Google Reader and it grew from there. I will skip the growing pains of this method, but trust me, it was hard to find a happy medium between being overwhelmed with content and feeling informed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List of Google Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/a-list-google-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2013 10:10:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/a-list-google-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>I used to love Google services and their policy of &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t be evil.&amp;rdquo; The anagram solver tells me that the phrase turns into the word &amp;lsquo;violented.&amp;rsquo; Well I definitely feel whatever that means.
I was a huge fan of Google Reader and Google Analytics. I even setup and managed google analytic accounts for websites that I created for clients. Not today.
I do understand it is probably cliche in the ever-growing hipster-tech community to be anti-google but I really don&amp;rsquo;t want to have my digital life attached to a single service where I am the product, which is also the reason I have a largely vacant Facebook account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Goal</title>
      <link>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/the-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamescampbell.us/posts/the-goal/</guid>
      <description>The goal should be do create things that make you happy.
Destroy and otherwise ignore the things that don&amp;rsquo;t.
Never stop noticing the small things.
Never be too busy to be able to talk to a stranger about nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
